I'm good geez talk about power
that was one heck of a block he made hey ginger we need you out there I know coach lost in the crowd
Jetball!
What?
Huh?
Number 10 isn't running up
Get lost in the crowd
Nice kill Asahi!
Right diving drills guys
We won that set
Force of habit sorry
That's good we finally managed to take a set
Yeah
That's seal walks
It looked to me like they actually hesitated for a second before they went for the block on that one
Up until now anytime Kageyama was setting
Hinata wouldn't be a part of the synchronized attacks
Because he would be running up at a faster tempo
Right while everyone else is running on first tempo
Hinata was always on minus tempo
Everyone is watching for that super quick attack
And it gets their guard up the first time they see it
But they're even more wary when they expect it
But right now we're up against Daytech
They might change up their block formation for strategic reasons
But it's rare for that formation to be disrupted by another team
What makes Daytech a great team
Is that even when Hinata hits his quick attack
They're able to shrug it off and move on
Yeah nothing phases those guys
They may be really good at blocking
But that doesn't mean they're trying to stop every attack
Even if they can't completely shut it down
They always have at least two blockers at the net
And they manage to at least touch Hinata super quick
They may not stop it completely
But they can narrow down where it goes
And then their floor defense can handle it
And so that means
They can bide their time
Until the last half of the game
When Hinata tires and they roof it
What was that?
Karasuno will be helpless to stop them
The ideal sequence for Daytech's ultimate triumph
Hey whose team are you on anyway?
With Hinata constantly getting scores
I'd expect them to start second guessing their blocks
But...
We're in the fourth set already
And I honestly can't say I'm seeing a lot of uncertainty
Yeah they're a real damn resilient team
And that is exactly why
I know coach
Lost in the crowd
Yeah
That sounds good to me
You two
The very first time I saw your quick attack
I thought it was incredible
Hm?
It was love at first sight
A quick that could be done from anywhere
With speed that laughs in the face of any defense
And terrifies all blockers
I mean...
I really thought speed was everything but...
When you're up against master reed blockers
All that blazing speed does for you
Is immediately eliminate you from the list of possible attackers
Mm
For Hinata more than anyone
Speed is his greatest weapon
I didn't think he'd volunteer to slow down
Just because a player knows a strategy will work
Doesn't mean he's actually gonna wanna carry it out
There's no guarantee that a weapon that worked in the beginning
Will keep working until the end
I have to keep moving forward
I have to keep going
My greatest weapon is that no one can catch me
If they adapt to me
Then I'll adapt to them
The one who stops adapting
Is the one who gets left behind
Untouched!
Got it!
There it is again
Hinata's not running forward
I'm still here
I'm still right here
Until the very end
Let them think it could be me
Until the last second
Yes!
Daichi!
Nice kill!
Daytech's blockers are watching Hinata even more closely
Nice kill Daichi!
I mean
It's basically like a kid who's begging for attention suddenly getting all quiet
Concentrate boys!
You can handle it
It's not like they're doing anything you've never seen before
That's right
Tsukishima and Hinata are doing just what they've always done with synchronized attacks
Coconut!
Right!
But...
That's too far!
Sorry!
It's a dink!
Cover!
Kageyama!
That was so fast!
Minus tempo baby!
We never said we wouldn't use it!
Woo!
Yeah!
Ah!
Man he just stood there!
Ouch Kokinigawa!
I know how that feels!
You know I noticed something!
The superquick really stands out after he's been blended in like that for a while!
In reed blocking what you're looking for on every play is where the ball is going!
But the ball itself is not the only thing you're watching!
The ball after it's been received!
The spikers who are about to attack!
And of course the setter!
Your eyes need to take in all that information instantaneously.
And so our plan is to give them too much information to process.
Hinata is absolutely perfect for that.
He's extremely annoying to play against.
You're always wondering, where is he headed?
When will he make his move?
And of course, our brilliant setter, Kageyama, isn't going to give anything away early.
Thanks to him, Hinata is able to attack from anywhere at any time.
And after he's been hiding away from attack to attack,
the minus tempo approach suddenly bears its fangs.
Um, excuse me.
I'm not sure if this is relevant or not, but once I heard former Kojook I say.
I'll be honest here.
Munchkin's minus tempo attack is definitely impressive on its own,
but they could do so much more with that thing.
Or something like that anyway.
Annoying old fart.
Yeah!
That last one was the best super quick attack of the whole day!
That one point's not going to make or break this game.
Huh?
But because of that one point, Daytech is going to pay a little bit more attention to Hinata.
That will make it just a little bit easier to score from the sides.
And of course, the more we manage to score from the sides,
the more the blockers will second-guess themselves.
Hmph.
And if we're lucky,
those blockers will get more and more impatient and start guest-blocking.
Then their defensive system falls apart.
Huh?
It's the ideal sequence for Karasuno's ultimate victory story!
Don't interrupt me, Tadashi.
Oops, sorry, my B.
Keep your focus.
This next set is the last one we have time for today.
Yes, sir!
Manbun, if you get tired, hang in there.
Hold form.
Right.
I'm setting it just like always.
There's some sort of problem?
Aw, poor Suki's dying out there.
Looks to me like his tank is just about empty for the day.
And he ate lunch and everything.
Hey, don't talk about Suki like he's you!
Sorry, but I'm not a robot or some monster version of Hinata, so...
Your job is to know how your teammates are doing.
Right.
Cover!
Tanaka!
Left, left!
A cross shot.
It's hopeless, you guys!
I just can't do anything right today!
You losing confidence?
You got this!
It may have gone out, but it was still a great line shot.
I was sure he was going to do a cross shot.
Holy crap!
Looks like Kageyama learned encouragement!
Nah, I don't think it was really encouragement.
I think he meant to call you a moron.
Nah, what's wrong with me?
You still got a long way to go, Futakuchi.
How long are you going to be here?
Don't you worry!
We're free all day!
Uh...
Okay.
Me?
Is it my turn?
Is it me?
It's my turn, right?
My turn?
Me?
Yeah, Tadashi has definitely gotten over his nerves.
Of course, I can obviously rely on somebody like that.
I mean, he's itching to get in there, but then...
Hisashi!
Put it over, Hisashi!
Oba!
Sorry!
I did it!
We're going to have to do something about our awful receives.
You've got this, Hisashi!
That's out!
All right, kid.
Don't freak out every time I call on you.
Especially when you're going to score points.
Right.
The next time you hide from me,
I'm making you sit next to me for the entire game.
Yes, sir.
Oh!
Minus tempo!
Damn, Iota is so freakin' awesome!
Got it!
A first tempo synchronized attack.
Or not!
Watch, Tin!
Is it for real this time?
He's here!
I'm gonna stop him!
Nice kill!
Did I imagine that?
It looked like he lured the blocker away on purpose.
He knew the blockers would react to the super quick,
so he acted like he was going to attack again to get him to go over there.
No.
He's always 100% ready to hit the ball.
That's what makes it so easy for him to bait the other team.
Was it coincidence?
Or intuition?
Either way, I'm the one who actually sent the ball over to Asahi,
so I get the credit no matter what.
Hmm?
What?
Asahi!
The strongest wall in the prefecture.
He's even bigger and stronger than he was back in second year.
But somehow, I'm not scared.
Asahi!
Three blockers!
Do it, Asahi!
Asahi!
Oh, that's some big time power!
It's not only power.
Thank you for the game!
Make sure you take the right balls.
Yes, sir!
Hey, you're really good. I bet you practice all the time, but you never tape your hands up or anything.
Do your fingers not hurt? Because I gotta tell you, man, I hurt my nails all the time.
Now I even tape them all up just to be safe.
I work on my finger strength, like with finger push-ups and stuff.
Taping my fingers feels weird, so I avoid it as much as I can.
My fingertips especially. Even a fraction of a millimeter between my fingers and the ball, and it just doesn't feel right.
Which is why I'm very rigorous about my fingertip and nail care.
About your nail care?
I'll start mine today!
You won't last the rest of the week.
Koga Manawa?
So close. It's Koga Nagawa.
Koga Nagawa, what's your highest jump reach?
Well, um, I think it was 340 centimeters.
The last time I measured, it was months ago, so I could maybe go higher now.
From one high point to another.
Meaning his sets only have to cover the shortest distance possible.
Koga Nagawa, see ya!
Yeah!
Well, good luck at the Spring Nationals.
Thanks. We appreciate that.
Man, those date tech guys are still pretty terrifying.
I don't want to meet them on a dark night.
Come on, Moniwa seems like a nice enough guy.
No, dude. He's always got those two massive second-year goons at his side.
You know...
Maybe I'll grow me a man-beard.
That's how you think you're gonna compete?
Good work, guys!
Thank you, sir!
Go easy on individual work.
Yes, sir!
Especially those of you who bike over a mountain.
Nishinoya!
Hmm?
I'll help you with your practice again tonight.
Come on, Hisashi! One more!
Hang on a sec!
I can't...
Your practice isn't really practice until your heart rate goes up!
Oh, I hate you.
I don't think I've ever seen Nishinoya this dressed out, even during a match.
Take this!
That was cool!
Hey, Kageyama?
When you're receiving, what are you thinking about?
Hmm.
The ways that I'm about to murder the ball.
I'm not sure that's helpful.
Say, Nishinoya.
You don't have to force yourself to get good at overhands.
I'm pretty sure you can still get by with your underhand receives.
Honestly, I used to think it'd be sweet to receive every ball underhanded.
And I thought I could pull it off, too.
But...
I can still go higher.
And now that I know I have options available to not try them all out, well, that'd be boring.
Huh?
Man.
Somehow you always say the coolest stuff.
I do want to be on the court more.
But I don't want it bad enough to screw it all up, though.
Well...
Then again...
Nishinoya is struggling to hit my serves right now.
I'll help you practice, Nishinoya.
Nishinoya.
I take back what I said.
This practice is for me.
I'm gonna serve the ball so hard.
He'll never get it.
What is it?
Hisashi's getting better.
More and more consistent with serving the ball to one spot.
I think he's aiming it there.
I can't let him beat me.
There's nothing wrong with having more good players on the team.
And he's not replacing you or anything.
Uh...
Yeah, but that's not what I meant.
Oh, okay.
I wish I could practice receiving and spiking at the same time.
Whenever I can practice with Kageyama, I really just want to spike.
But...
They tell me Coach Grandpa Yukai's place is gonna be closed for a while.
But hey!
I am an expert at practicing by myself!
Hey Shouya, whatcha doin'?
These are my ultimate lonely passing drills.
I wanna try!
But then it wouldn't be a lonely drill anymore.
You couldn't do them anyway, Natsu.
But hey P.E.
I'm like the best at everything!
Okay, see that?
Hm?
It's a soft volleyball.
Start by bouncing the ball up.
Then keep the ball in the air while you lie down on the ground.
And keep going while you stand back up.
Simple enough, right?
Then do it again!
Okay, give it your best shot!
Oh!
Try it again in another century!
Now!
Let a throw show you how it's done!
Oh!
Simple enough, right?
Then do it again. Okay, give it your best shot
Try it again in another century now let a throw show you how it's done
How do you like that good job show you
Seems like you're friends with the ball now
Before when you did stuff you and the ball were strangers
We're friends
Oh
僕は知らない
深など 笑えばいいさ
そんな言葉 僕は知らない
I guess we're finally there then
Next time, everyone's night